Temi Kelani

AWS ARCHITECT

temikelani@icloud.com, +1 (646) 854-5958

A Cloud Architect with 3+ years experience architecting, designing, and implementing effective and performant AWS solutions, who enjoys working with companies to build the most cost-effective and efficient infrastructure for their business needs - using only the tools they need.

CONTACT

- Email
- LinkedIn
- GitHub
- +1 (646) 854-5958
- Remote Anywhere in The World

CERTIFICATES

AWS Associate Solutions Architect

EDUCATION

BENG ELECTRICAL ENGINEERING

Glasgow Caledonian University United Kingdom 2015

TECH STACK

- Languages: Python, Bash, JavaScript
- OS: Linux
- IAC: CloudFormation, Terraform, Ansible
- CI/CD: GitHub Actions, Circle-CI
- AWS: EC2, Lambda, Auto Scaling, ELB, EBS, S3, VPC, DynamoDB, RDS, SNS, SQS, Event Bridge, CloudFront, CloudWatch, CloudTrail, Config, SSM, IAM, CLI, Route 53, Backup, CDK
- In Training: EKS, Docker Kubernetes

CAREER HIGLIGHTS

Project Portfolio

· A link to featured Projects on GitHub.

WORK EXPERIENCE

AWS Consultant | Upwork | 2020 - Present

Producing custom AWS Lambda scripts for:

- · Resource management: Identifying and deleting unused resources,
- User permissions and management: Adding/Removing users from groups, creating/deleting users, rotating access keys
- Filtering resources: Based on custom criteria (tags, SSM, AMI id, region, date/time)
- Automating resource and DR backups (EC2, S3, DynamoDB, RDS, EBS): On-demand, scheduled or event triggered using DynamoDB, AWS Lambda, Event Bridge Rules, AWS Backup etc
- CRUD/Cron web scraping Jobs and S3 data dumps

Custom configuration (CloudFormation/Terraform) templates for a range of solutions including:

- Monitoring and alerts via SNS, Cloud Watch, and AWS Lambda
- Configuring multi-AZ/region fault tolerant solutions architecture
- Deploying highly available web applications with EC2, VPC, Lambda, CloudFront, API Gateway

Training Cloud Architect | Per Scholas | 2020 - 2021

Per Scholas is an AWS re/Start company that provides real-world, scenario-based learning, labs, and coursework

- · Voted team lead
- Built, maintained, and automated the provisioning of cloud infrastructure utilizing CloudFormation, terraform, Ansible and CICD with GitHub Actions and AWS CodeBuild Suite
- Leveraged AWS cloud services, including EC2, ELB, ASG, and S3, to build and secure scalable and flexible systems designed to handle expected and unexpected load bursts.
- Created, onboarded, and managed users, permissions, directories, and files in Linux environment
- Provided security compliance through automated programmatic remediation using Config, SSM and Lambda.
- Conceived, developed, and configured network infrastructure within VPC with public and private subnets, configured routing tables, security groups, and internet gateway.
- Defined and implemented monitoring metrics and logging systems using CloudWatch, Config, and CloudTrail and executed Python script utilizing Cron.

Data Analyst Intern | Hudson Meridian | 2018 - 2020

- Responsible for maintaining excluded worker status during the Covid-19 pandemic with data and dashboards resulting in 99% uptime and continued compliance with New York Department of Buildings Regulations
- Reproducing data collection and procedures at multiple job sites
- Designed and maintained data ingestion pipelines freeing up 40% of the workday
- Monitoring inventory and generated alerts based on volume and for upcoming events
- Maintained database of employees, inventory, and incidents.